<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Enfield Yatra]]></title>
  <link href="http://enfieldyatra.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://enfieldyatra.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-05T16:18:32+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://enfieldyatra.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[EnfieldYatra]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tamhini Ghat - S01E02]]></title>
    <link href="http://enfieldyatra.github.io/blog/2014/08/14/tamhini-ghat-s01e02/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://enfieldyatra.github.io/blog/2014/08/14/tamhini-ghat-s01e02</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are searching for place, where you can have short monsoon trip, then Tamini Ghat is a great option. It is the perfect getaway if you want to enjoy the ride to fullest without investing your full weekend. It is on the crest of Western Ghat mountain ranges, nearly 100Kms from Pune and 150Kms from Mumbai. Tamhini Ghat Road is located between Mulsi to Tamhini route which connects Konkan from Pune. The entire Ghat section is almost 15 to 20 Km.</p>

<p>We started our journey at 9 am on a Saturday morning. We were totally amazed by scenic waterfalls, awesome Mulsi Lake and dense greenery that covered the entire stretch. The roads are mostly good except very few sections where the roads were in a messed up state due to heavy rains. As the route involves mostly Ghat like roads,  if you are visiting in peak monsoons, you need to be cautious about driving.</p>

<p>Best thing about this Ghat is that at every turn, you get a chance to admire nature. You can’t stop yourself from taking frequent breaks, just to enjoy the scenic surroundings like the amazing waterfalls. View you get to see is so breathtaking, that you just want to capture everything in your mind. It will give you so much peace, that you will get totally refreshed. The mountains are totally covered by greenery and a thick layer of clouds surrounds them. While riding you get a feeling that you are going to touch the clouds.</p>

<p>The taste of ‘Bhutta’ in the rains is so awesome, that you can just keep on eating it. The  best thing is that there is no dearth of vendors and you can easily purchase a ‘bhutta’ at every few kms. Apart from this there are many hotels where you can enjoys ‘Chai’ and ‘Pakodas’, as well as other maharashtrian dishes.</p>

<p>The route is such that you can continue to go as far as you want, or as per your time constraints you can take U-turn and enjoy the ride back to Pune. The amazing part is that you get to see whole route again, but in different shades of sunlight and clouds. While returning to Pune we encountered very dense fog, and hence had to drive very slow. The situation was quite difficult, as we were having problems with visibility for distance beyond a meter.</p>

<p>As I always say though this ghat is amazing, along with admiring nature, also keep an eye on the road and the traffic. You should drive slowly and carefully so that your driving does not harm yourself or others.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kolhapur to Pune, First Page of My Travel Diary]]></title>
    <link href="http://enfieldyatra.github.io/blog/2014/07/31/kolhapur-to-pune-first-page-of-my-travel-diary/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://enfieldyatra.github.io/blog/2014/07/31/kolhapur-to-pune-first-page-of-my-travel-diary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kolhapur to Pune turned out to be my first long drive. The journey I had while driving to Pune was wonderful. I would say it will surely be one of the best journeys of my life as it is the first page in my travel diary.</p>

<p>One thing I learnt from this ride, destination is never as important as the journey you go through while arriving to your destination. After giving a thought I realized that this thing is not only about a ride, it’s applicable for your life as well. At the end you only remember the times where you have all of your experiences, memories and joys to reach to the final point. The time you take to reach to destination just keeps on building excitement and thats the feeling which makes your journey memorable.</p>

<p>And the day arrived, 27 July, 2014, It was just after a couple of week from the day I got my machine.  As it was my first long ride and that to in peak rainy season where nature come outside with all it’s beauty and greenery. I was totally excited about the journey, but having hell lot of questions in mind. I was totally blank about the things which one should take care before going for a long drive. While reading about it I came across various experiences expressed by riders. Its just like a awesome feeling where you start knowing your partner more and more in a relationship. I hope, I will come more close to my enfield as we both travel more journeys together.</p>

<p>Journey from kolhapur to pune has a quite a distance of 225 kms. This whole track NH4 is very decent track having throughout 6 lane road. It will not be the case where you will have the adventure ride in this journey but you will definitely have very comfortable and pleasant ride where you can enjoy the company of Sanhyadri mountain range  in the whole journey. Gurudatta, my friend, was pillion rider for this ride. We were so lucky that we had my first long ride in this beautiful climate.</p>

<p>It was a peak of rainy season. There were no lack green colour any where. Its just amazing feeling of riding your bike in rainy season. You could see all the different shades in sky. You could see heavy rain in mountain. You could see nature taking new life and flourishing itself with all the possible beauty. It’s just perfect combo pack for you, awesome road and so the climate. I agree rainy season is the best season to have long rides on your bike to enjoy the awesomeness of nature but at the same time you should be totally patient and and always keep safety in your mind as roads might get too much slippery in period.</p>

<p>As road was smooth and comfortable, we never felt exhausted. We still keep on taking 5 10 minutes break after 60 70 kms. In between there are many good places like Karad, Satara Bhuinj where you can have good food and give rest to you and your bike. While we were passing Satara, bunch of fully armed bulleteers crossed us. It was feeling like we were knowing each other. Everyone was having so much discipline in there driving that it felt like all of them were giving respect to each other and thats exactly it should be. Riding is art and you should not spoil it by rash driving. It should be the journey that you enjoy, not the speed</p>

<p>After having this ride of whole 250+ kms, I fell in love with this machine again. It is totally sturdy and steady bike. You get total comfort and pleasure while riding it. At no point of time you feel strain or get bored in the ride. After a ride also you remain as fresh as the time where you star journey. This bike will definitely be my long time partner. Hopefully we both will come on the road to meet nature in this amazing season soon. Till then be a Rider as there are hell lot of things to meet and visit in this world. Enjoy your life, Ride safe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Enfield]]></title>
    <link href="http://enfieldyatra.github.io/blog/2014/07/18/why-enfield/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://enfieldyatra.github.io/blog/2014/07/18/why-enfield</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ummm &hellip; . People always ask “why you went for royal enfield when there are other bikes available in the market ?” Its really hard to answer this question because you can&rsquo;t explain it, one has to feel it. Royal Enfield is THE bike which is &ldquo;Made like a Gun and goes like a Bullet&rdquo;</p>

<p>Craze, Comfort, Passion, Thrill, Power, Thump, Love, Beauty, there are so many things you feel about royal enfield that you fall short of words to express them.
The bond between bulleteers and their machine always fascinates me. Its really awesome. “Bull” as they call it, is always treated way more than a vehicle. Emotional relationship which riders develop towards their machine can only be understood by those who have a similar passion. “Love is what you feel when you like something as much as your motorcycle” perfectly explains this relationship. Because of this passion there is different kind of brotherhood amongst all RE’ians. That’s why if you need an explanation for why its enfield, you won’t get it.</p>

<p>Many say it has mechanical problems, is overrated and overpriced, delivers lower mileage, vibrates a lot, makes hell lot of noise etc. For a bulleteer, its never about money or mileage. As I said, it’s always about the bond and love for the bullet which you can&rsquo;t measure in terms of money.</p>

<p>For many people, sound of Bullet is very displeasing.  But it is as melodious as music for a royal enfield owner. Every time your heart starts beating with the strokes of your machine, you get feel of having born a new life.</p>

<p>Royal enfield has the capacity to perform exceptionally well in all beautiful and tough terrains of india. Khardung La in Ladakh - the highest motorable road on earth is one such place. For this very reason, the Indian Army is also using it extensively in such terrains since a long period of time. I think royal enfield can give you the desired comfort and pleasure through the most amazing rides from the northern extreme Himalayas to southern coastal area and from the western deserts of Rajasthan to eastern hilly terrains on Darjeeling.</p>

<p>To own a royal enfield is not just an event in your life, it’s a life long journey. For me, it is always this bike and long roads which give inner peace. Through every journey you will get amazed by finding new perspective towards your life. I can clearly state royal enfield is the perfect companion for that.</p>

<p>So to summarize, if you need an answer for Why Enfield ? just go and ride the BULL once, you will understand all the feelings I tried to express.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
